Ducarmel Rodchild Zephyr organical-action-color: Ducarmel Rodchild Zephyr organical-action-color: blue; organical-a

<u>@linkedin</u> <u>@github.com</u> <u>@portfolio</u>

Skills

Programming Languages : HTML & CSS (including Bootstrap), JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5 Canvas, C/C++/C#
Frameworks : JavaScript Web App Frameworks (Knockout), JavaScript Testing Frameworks (Jasmine)

Version Control Systems : Git

Operating Systems : Linux, Windows

Other : Critical Rendering Path, 60FPS Rendering, Object-Oriented Programming, Chrome Developer Tools.

Projects

- A PDF-file design mockup has been replicated in HTML and CSS. I developed a responsive website using responsive
 web design principles and responsive images. Descriptions, images and links for each of the portfolio projects to be
 completed throughout the course of the Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree are displayed.
- Online resume using JavaScript and jQuery. Master the language's syntax through a series of challenges. Each
 multipart problem mimics a real-life challenge that front-end developers face. I have been required to write clean code and
 to apply my knowledge of variables, objects, JSON, functions and control flow to successfully solve the challenges.
- Classic Arcade Game Clone using Object-Oriented JavaScript and HTML5 Canvas. I have received visual assets and
 a game loop engine; using these tools I had to add a number of entities to the game including the player characters and
 enemies to recreate the classic arcade game Frogger.
- Website Performance and Browser Rendering Optimization. I have optimized a provided website with a number of optimization- and performance-related issues so that it achieves a target PageSpeed score and runs at 60 frames per second.
- Neighborhood Map using AJAx and JavaScript Design Patterns. I have developed a single-page application featuring
 a map of my neighborhood. I have added additional functionality to this application, including: map markers to identify
 popular locations or places I'd like to visit, a search function to easily discover these locations, and a listview to support
 simple browsing of all locations. I have researched and implemented third-party APIs that provide additional information
 about each of these locations (such as StreetView images, Wikipedia articles, Yelp reviews, etc).
- Feed Reader Testing using JavaScript Testing. In this project, I have learn about testing with Javascript. Testing is an important part of the development process and many organizations practice a standard known as "test-driven development" or TDD. This is when developers write tests first, before they ever start developing their application.

Relevant Experience

Programmer 2010-2011

GOVERNMENT OF CANADA, DEFENCE MINISTRY, Montréal, Quebec

- I created data table and stored procedures with MS SQL Server 2005.
- I improved existing MS Access applications with .NET applications using C#.

Web developer 2009-2010

FORUM ÉCONOMIQUE DE VERDUN, Montréal, Quebec

• I created and launched a set of web sites for the organization.

Technical support 2006-2009

ADP ROSELAND, New-Jersey

- I managed linux operating systems
- I achieved excellent relation with users dealing with software problems
- I managed website maintenance and update
- I improved technical documentation.

Education

Computer Programmer, Bois de Boulogne College, Montreal, Quebec

Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree:

Courses Taken: Intro to HTML and CSS, Responsive Web Design Fundamentals, Responsive Images, Version Control, JavaScript Basics, Intro to jQuery, Hosting Projects with GitHub Pages, Object-Oriented JavaScript, HTML5 Canvas, Website Performance Optimization, Browser Rendering Optimization, Intro to AJAX, JavaScript Design Patterns, JavaScript Testing.